Brian Salehi

Age 26

Email

salehibrian@gmail.

Phone

+98 903 121 8938

Website

briansalehi.ir

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/
briansalehi

Github

github.com/
briansalehi

Address

No 15, Mojdeh st., Pasdaran st., Tehran, Iran

Brian Salehi

Software Engineer

Professional Summary I'm a Linux application and system programmer working on UI applications, 3D graphics programming, image processing and embedded devices using C and C++ programming languages, and a few advanced development tools to do my work as professionally as I can. I'm also a huge fan of open source and I usually spend some of my spare time contributing to open source projects. Last but not least I have a notable discipline to balance out the energy I put in my work and studies in a cyclic manner so that I can always bring new skillset and innovations to work and become more experienced in them.

Experiences

Arad Research and Development Company

aradtechs.com

Software Engineer

05/2021 - present

Updated: December 1, 2021

Contributed to many projects in a professional team from programming desktop applications, designing user interfaces, programming 3D graphical applications and web services to documenting each of these projects extensively.

Freelance milextone.ir

Software Engineer, Technical Trainer

03/2019 - 04/2021

I had 11 students from freshman year of college to PhD candidate in Iran, Germany and Poland, teaching programming and administration.

Manzoomeh Negaran Holdings

seller.ir

Software Engineer, Database Specialist

06/2016 - 6/2017

Designed, implemented and maintained the back-end and database services of an industrial webstore.

Cooperations

Bioengineering Laboratory

Poland (undisclosed)

Software Engineer

08/2020 - present

Consulting technical solutions for development of computational services.

Sarmad Business Services Company

Iran (sarmadbs.com)

System Administrator, Database Specialist

04/2021 - 06/2021

Consulting technical solutions to maintain systems and services.

Brian Salehi

Age 26

Email

salehibrian@gmail.

Phone

+98 903 121 8938

Website

briansalehi.ir

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/
briansalehi

Github

github.com/
briansalehi

Address

No 15, Mojdeh st., Pasdaran st., Tehran, Iran

Skills

Technical Skills

C Programming

Linux interface programming and developing high performance services

C++ Programming

Writing programs using STL or Boost and recent language standards

x86_64 Assembly Programming

Writing processor specific high performance procedures and data vectorization

Qt, QML, JavaScript

Developing full-featured cross-platform graphical user interfaces

OpenGL, GLSL

3D graphics programming and developing game engines

OpenCV

Developing image and video processing applications

Linux Administration, Bash Scripting

Configuring, automating, administering and securing Linux systems

PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB

Designing, developing and administering relational and non-relational databases

Tools

Git, Docker, Kubernetes

Using Git workflows and applying containarization and continous delivery

GCC, GDB

Using compilation optimization and debugging techniques

Make, CMake, CTest, CPack, CDash

Adapting projects to auto-compiling, testing, packaging and monitoring

Doxygen, UML, PlantUML

Writing precise tutorial like documentations containing UML diagrams

Atlassian CI/CD Tools

Maintaining, testing and documenting code base in Atlassian tools

Miscellaneous Skills

Vim

My default text editor for coding and configuring

Python

Using for educational purposes in machine learning

LaTeX

Writing documents, specially this resume

Brian Salehi

Age 26

Email

salehibrian@gmail.

Phone

+98 903 121 8938

Website

briansalehi.ir

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/ briansalehi

Github

github.com/
briansalehi

Address

No 15, Mojdeh st., Pasdaran st., Tehran, Iran

Education

Islamic Azad University, Tehran North

iau-tnb.ac.ir

MSc. of Computer Science, Software Engineering 09/2021 - 06/2023

Islamic Azad University, Tehran East

iauet.ac.ir

BSc. of Computer Science

09/2016 - 06/2021

Certificates

Fanavaran Anisa Ins. anisa.co.ir

Embedded Linux 5/2021 - present

Fanavaran Anisa Ins. anisa.co.ir

Linux Application Development 5/2021 - present

Fanavaran Anisa Ins. anisa.co.ir

LPIC-3: Linux Security 3/2017 - present

Fanavaran Anisa Ins. anisa.co.ir

LPIC-2: Linux Networks 3/2016 - present

Fanavaran Anisa Ins. anisa.co.ir

LPIC-1: Linux Systems 3/2015 - present

Certificate files can be found at briansalehi.ir/certs

Interests

Technical

Image processing, machine learning, graphics programming, user interfaces, kernel hacking, embedded Linux, software design, algorithms, PCB and hardware design, mathematics, quantum mechanics, philosophy, psychiatry

Personal

Playing electric guitar, reading books, swimming, biking, running, hiking

Languages

English Fluent

I have a strong studying background in English.

(PoC: briansalehi.ir/library).

German Basic

I'm currently learning German to the extent of living in Germany.

References

Dr. Farhang Jaryani

fjayani@yahoo.com

Faculty of Computer Science, Arak University, Iran